Let's get started with AOSp build.
In this tutorial we are going to cover three topics.
The first one is setting up a build environment.
The second one is to download the AOSp source code, and the third one is to build the source code.
And finally starting the emulator and having a quick tour walkthrough.
Before we start with the AOSp download process, we need to install a few packages to support the AOSp
download and build process.
I am now in source dot Android.
Basically, we need to run these commands the sudo apt get install commands to install these packages.
So these packages are needed for downloading and building the Android open source project system.
So based on your operating system like this, if you have ubuntu 18.04, then you have to use this command.
And if you have ubuntu 14.04 then this one and so on with 12.04, 10.04, 10.10 and 11.10.
Okay.
So in my case I'm using ubuntu 20.0 4.2.
LDS.
So I am using the same 20.0 4.2 LDS.
So I am using the same version of ubuntu.
Sudo apt install commands required for 18.04.
So even if you have the latest ubuntu, still this install command should be sufficient.
Okay, so in case if you have an older one, please use any of these.
And if you have 18.04 or above use this apt install command.
Okay.
So let's copy this and open up a terminal window.
We simply go ahead and paste it.
Enter.
So you need your password.
Yes.
So in my case many of these packages are already installed.
So I guess there will be only a few things which will get updated.
Yeah, it seems to be updating something.
Let's see.
Yeah.
So it's done.
So now I have installed all those required packages.
Let's go further.